<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random_thoughts on huhaha</title>
    <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/tags/random_thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random_thoughts on huhaha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.huhaha.com/tags/random_thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decision</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/decision/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-make-a-damn-decision-any-decision&#34;&gt;Just make a damn decision, any decision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of months back the wife took the kids to a local library and recycled many old kids books. Somehow one single book got missed and left in the car trunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time when we opened the trunk taking things out or putting things in, we saw this lonely book. Months passed and the book remained to be in the trunk. We thought about tossing it, going to the library to recycle it again, or just bringing it back to the house. We did nothing, because none of the options seemed to be “the winner”. We were “paralyzed” by this so called no-good-choice among many choices situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ownership</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/ownership/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a typical fall storm in central New Jersey, my lawn was covered with fallen leaves and tree branches. It’s just such a headache because I have to pick up all the fallen branches by hand before I could get on my ride-on lawn mower and clean up the leaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;lawn picture 01&#34; src=&#34;https://blog.huhaha.com/Lawn01.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Lawn after a storm&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I asked my two kids for help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this is not their first time for such a task and they know perfectly well what was expected of them and quickly got on the job.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Play Hard”</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/play-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/play-hard/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was about two months ago, my son’s second last game for the 2020 season of his soccer travel team. I don’t even remember the score of the game, but only our trip back home from the game. The trip was an hour long. But only a few minutes in, I saw my son, from the rear view mirror, was silently weeping in the back seat. I knew he wasn’t hurt in the game and performed okay, from my perspective, – nothing especially good or bad. But I did notice that his coach had a short conversation with him during a substitution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meaning of life</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/meaning-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/meaning-of-life/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-son-11-asked-me-this-million-dollar-question-whats-the-meaning-of-life&#34;&gt;My son, 11, asked me this million-dollar question, “what’s the meaning of life?”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got another opportunity to “chat” with my son yesterday, which I would never get it wasted. 😀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was towards the end of the day, after he spent a lot of time during the day on absolutely nothing except all the “screen time” (phone games, PC games, switch games, youtube game plays, online chat with his friends, etc.), and I was able to ask him this question:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Right or wrong</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/right-or-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/right-or-wrong/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;right-or-wrong--all-about-character&#34;&gt;Right or wrong – all about character&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I wrote in a previous blog, “So the criterion of making a choice is really all about right or wrong, rather than how you feel (like or dislike),” a message I’ve repeatedly given to my son and hope one day he could take it to heart 😀. This line seems to be a perfect prelude for a conversation I just had with my son more recently:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Thinking, Or Not</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/strategic-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/strategic-thinking/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;True story…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The husband enjoys Costco Butter Pound Cakes. In a morning he opened up a new one and, like what he always did, cut each cake into three even-sized pieces so that for the next nine days he could simply pick one piece each day for breakfast, as opposed to just cute out one piece for the day and do the same one-piece cut for the next eight days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“任性” (ren’xing)</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/ren-xing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/ren-xing/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a Chinese phrase “任性” and I found it’s hard to have a matching English translation. Google Translate gives me words like “capricious” or “willfulness”, which are really not what “任性” refers to in terms of its implication of someone’s behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day when I was having a conversation with my son and attempting to convince him doing his homework instead of playing video games, I suddenly figured out how to explain the meaning of this particular Chinese word to him, although that needing much more effort in English. I explained that when you make a choice between homework and video game, it’s not about which one you like or dislike, it’s really about what’s the right thing to do at that particular moment. So the criterion of making a choice is really all about right or wrong, rather than how you feel (like or dislike). If you can’t make the right choice based on this standard, this means you are too “任性” in Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there anything to thank for?</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/things-to-thank-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/things-to-thank-for/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a few hours to kill in this Thanksgiving Eve, while waiting in a local YMCA for my daughter’s swimming practice. It seems to be a perfect time and a perfect pause from busy daily routines to list out things that I can thank for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there anything to thank for though, in this era full of confusion, in this life fully of stress, in this mind full of screaming? Is there any?!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space of safety</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/space-of-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/space-of-safety/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My son, Eric, plays soccer since he was little. He used to have scored the most in his first year travel team. He later moved on to a more competitive team and his position has been moved backwards and he now is the team’s “center back”. Although the coach has been giving him the opportunities to play forward positions, but he seems to struggle and always falls back to a defense position. Make no mistakes, he did well in this position and has been given the most “game time” among his teammates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boys will be bugs</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/boys-bugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/boys-bugs/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My relationship with my daughter has not been going too well as what I hoped for lately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is 14 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means I suggested that her age was the problem. My daughter and I used to be close. When I had to travel overseas for work frequently and needed to leave the house really early in the morning. It was her getting up and sending me to the door with tears in her eyes. That’s back then, of course, when she was about 7 or 8.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspective vs. Opinion</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/perspective-vs-opinion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/perspective-vs-opinion/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When in an disagreement, do you provide a perspective or an opinion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perspective&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a particular attitude toward or way of regarding something; a point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opinion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a view or judgment formed about something, not necessarily based on fact or knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;– Dictionary.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to tell the difference from their definitions, isn’t it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An opinion, especially a strong one, typically implies right from wrong, good from bad, and superiority from inferiority. In another word, there is often little room for ambiguity and options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/power/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/power/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was just one of those swim meets, hundreds of parents sitting upstairs, watching down their kids to compete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 9 years old girl got up on the starting block. In anticipation of the whistle, she fell into the pool. Realizing the mistake, she quickly swam back and climbed up. When she attempted to climb on the block again and be ready for the start, an official called her down and ordered her to wait on the side and watch the other girls to finish.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk about weather</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/talk-about-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/talk-about-weather/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-all-started-with-a-small-talk-about-weather&#34;&gt;It all started with a small talk about weather…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is early February in New Jersey. After a few historical cold days at around zero °F degrees, it shot right to the sixties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walking my daughter out of her piano lesson, she commented on the weather:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is crazy. This is exactly what’s been said about global warming. In a winter day, you got so cold, but the next day you got so warm.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Character</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/character/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/character/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I was checking my son’s reading homework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one question, it asked what are the characteristics of an astronaut – he was supposed to find the right answer from the story he just read. My son’s answer was,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Astronauts can be teachers, scientists, engineers, medical doctors, and sometimes pilots”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, he copied this sentence directly somewhere from the story and he copied from the wrong place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I explained to him,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/truth/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ability in finding truth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People’s ability in finding truth differ. There are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;people who can tell the truth ahead of all others and before all evidences are being presented;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;people who can recognize the truth when the facts are laid out in front them – the “Aha moment”;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;people who will never accept the truth when it is against their own will, even all the facts in the world are out there for them to see.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can we say that’s how we tell the difference between true leaders, responsible citizens, and if not conspirators must be fools?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potential</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/potential/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took my daughter to swimming when she was only two years old, which was mostly driven by the thought that swimming will give her a stronger lung – since she was suffering asthma at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward 11 years, her asthma has long gone, but she has kept on swimming and been competing on a regular basis. She has, however, always been in the middle of the “pack”, never shown a special talent in swimming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment, Asset, and Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/investment-asset-portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/investment-asset-portfolio/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Investment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the investing of money or capital in order to gain profitable returns, as interest, income, or appreciation in value; or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a devoting, using, or giving of time, talent, emotional energy, etc., as for a purpose or to achieve something&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;items of ownership convertible into cash; total resources of a person or business, as cash, notes and accounts receivable, securities, inventories, goodwill, fixtures, machinery, or real estate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portfolio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the total holdings of the securities, commercial paper, etc., of a financial institution or private investor&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accountability</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/accountability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/accountability/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Forgot which episode was it in the TV show “West Wing”. The context was that President Bartlet struggled with a decision to or not to send in special forces to rescue a soldier that was held in hostage in an African country. He finally gave the order to send in the rescue. The tragedy was that the helicopter of the special forces got shot down and more soldiers lost their lives as a result.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guilty until proven innocent</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/guilty-until-proven-innocent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/guilty-until-proven-innocent/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was traveling in Beijing two years ago and needed some cash. I went into a branch office of a local bank in a morning and fed my PNC bank debit card to the ATM machine. The machine “took” it and did not “spit out” any cash or my debit card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My return flight to the US was scheduled in the afternoon, so I needed to get my debit card back – quickly. Lucky for me the office did have clerks that were quite familiar this kind of issue and it was normally called that the ATM machine has “eaten” the card. All I needed was to provide proof of my identity that matches the information on the debit card and then I could get my card back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speak from heart</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/speak-from-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/speak-from-heart/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an oversimplified way, people speak in three different manners: spontaneous responses, filtered by logical thinking, and voice of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember when I was in graduate school, I was cleaning up the lab, which was supposed to be a shared job by all graduate students. A girl, who walked into the lab and saw what I was doing, causally questioned my motivation of doing that. I was quite annoyed to say the least because she was supposed to help me instead of mocking me. Well, the girl became my wife later…that’s another story for another day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike Riding</title>
      <link>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/bike-riding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.huhaha.com/posts/bike-riding/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Bike Riding&#34; src=&#34;https://blog.huhaha.com/bike-riding.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often rode bike with my own kids and sometimes neighbor’s kids too around our neighborhood. Came to a cross road I often asked, “who is going to take a lead and show us which way to go?” Not only no one volunteered, but the kids typically announced their strong opposition to lead, even including those who I considered outgoing in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I puzzle every single time when this happens. This is such a risk-free situation to make an easy decision for the group. But for the kids who I rode with it seemed to be such a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
